{
	"allQuestions": [{
		"id": 1,
		"question": "Android is -",
		"category": "android",
		"answer": ["a web browser", "an operating system", "a web server", "None of the above"],
		"correctAnswer": "an operating system"
	}, {
		"id": 2,
		"question": "Under which of the following Android is licensed?",
		"category": "android",
		"answer": ["OSS", "OSS", "Apache/MIT", "None of the above"],
		"correctAnswer": "Apache/MIT"
	}, {
		"id": 3,
		"question": " For which of the following Android is mainly developed?",
		"category": "android",
		"answer": ["Mobile devices", "Watch", "Desktops", "Servers"],
		"correctAnswer": "Mobile devices"
	}, {
		"id": 4,
		"question": "Which of the following is the first mobile phone released that ran the Android OS?",
		"category": "android",
		"answer": ["Google gPhone", "T - Mobile G1", "Samsung", "Motorola"],
		"correctAnswer": "T - Mobile G1"
	}, {
		"id": 5,
		"question": "Which of the following virtual machine is used by the Android operating system?",
		"category": "android",
		"answer": ["Simple virtual machine", "JVM", "Dalvik virtual machine", "None of the above"],
		"correctAnswer": "Dalvik virtual machine"
	}, {
		"id": 6,
		"question": "APK stands for -",
		"answer": ["Android Page Kit", "Android Phone Kit", "Android Package Kit", "None of the above"],
		"category": "android",
		"correctAnswer": "Android Package Kit"
	}, {
		"id": 7,
		"question": "What does API stand for?",
		"answer": ["Application Page Interface", "Application Programming Interface", "Android Programming Interface", "Android Page Interface"],
		"category": "android",
		"correctAnswer": "Application Programming Interface"
	}, {
		"id": 8,
		"question": "Which of the following converts Java byte code into Dalvik byte code?",
		"answer": ["Dex compiler", "Virtual Machine", "Mobile interpretive compiler (MIC)", "Dalvik converter"],
		"category": "android",
		"correctAnswer": "Dex compiler"
	}, {
		"id": 9,
		"question": "How can we stop the services in android?",
		"answer": ["By using system.exit() method", "By using the stopSelf() and stopService() method", "By using system.exit() method", "By using system.stop() method"],
		"category": "android",
		"correctAnswer": "By using the stopSelf() and stopService() method"
	}, {
		"id": 10,
		"question": "What is an activity in android?",
		"answer": ["android package", "android resourse", "android class", "A single screen in an application with supporting java/kotlin code"],
		"category": "android",
		"correctAnswer": "A single screen in an application with supporting java/kotlin code"
	}, {
		"id": 11,
		"question": "How can we kill an activity in android?",
		"answer": ["Using finishActivity(int requestCode)", "Using finish() method", "Neither (a) nor (b)", "Both (a) and (b)"],
		"category": "android",
		"correctAnswer": "Both (a) and (b)"
	}, {
		"id": 12,
		"question": "ADB stands for -",
		"answer": ["Android destroy bridge", "Android delete bridge", "Android debug bridge", "None of the above"],
		"category": "android",
		"correctAnswer": "Android debug bridge"
	}, {
		"id": 13,
		"question": "On which of the following, developers can test the application, during developing the android applications?",
		"answer": ["Physical android phone", "Third-party emulators", "Emulator included in Android SDK", "All of the above"],
		"category": "android",
		"correctAnswer": "All of the above"
	}, {
		"id": 14,
		"question": "Which of the following kernel is used in Android?",
		"answer": ["Redhat", "Linux", "Windows", "MAC"],
		"category": "android",
		"correctAnswer": "Linux"
	}, {
		"id": 15,
		"question": "Which of the following is the first callback method that is invoked by the system during an activity life-cycle?",
		"answer": ["onRestart() method", "onStart() method", "onCreate() method", "onAttach() method"],
		"category": "android",
		"correctAnswer": "onCreate() method"
	}, {
		"id": 16,
		"question": "Which of the following is not an activity lifecycle callback method?",
		"answer": ["onCreate() method", "onBackPressed() method", "onResume() method", "onCreate() method"],
		"category": "android",
		"correctAnswer": "onBackPressed() method"
	}, {
		"id": 17,
		"question": "We require an AVD to create an emulator. What does AVD stand for?",
		"answer": ["Android Virtual device", "Active Virtual display", "Android Virtual display", "Android Virtual display"],
		"category": "android",
		"correctAnswer": "Android Virtual device"
	}, {
		"id": 18,
		"question": "Does android support other languages than java?",
		"answer": ["Can't Say", "No", "Yes", "May be "],
		"category": "android",
		"correctAnswer": "Yes"
	}, {
		"id": 19,
		"question": "What is the use of content provider in Android?",
		"answer": ["For sending the data from an application to another application", "For sending messages to other application", "For storing the data in the database", "For sending the data from an application to another application"],
		"category": "android",
		"correctAnswer": "For sending the data from an application to another application"
	}, {
		"id": 20,
		"question": "AAPT stands for -",
		"answer": ["Android Action Packaging Tool", "Android Activity Packaging Tool", "Android Asset Packaging Tool", "None of the above"],
		"category": "android",
		"correctAnswer": "Android Asset Packaging Tool"
	}, {
		"id": 21,
		"question": "NDK stands for -",
		"answer": ["Native Development Kit", "New Development kit", "Native Design Kit", "None of the above"],
		"category": "android",
		"correctAnswer": "Native Development Kit"
	}, {
		"id": 22,
		"question": "Which of the following is contained in the src folder?",
		"answer": ["Manifest", "Java source code", "XML", "None of the above"],
		"category": "android",
		"correctAnswer": "Java source code"
	}, {
		"id": 23,
		"question": "Which of the following method is used to handle what happens after clicking a button?",
		"answer": ["onCreate", "onSelect", "onClick", "onClicked"],
		"category": "android",
		"correctAnswer": "onClick"
	}, {
		"id": 24,
		"question": "Which of the following android component displays the part of an activity on screen?",
		"answer": ["Intent", "Fragment", "Service", "Intent"],
		"category": "android",
		"correctAnswer": "Fragment"
	}, {
		"id": 25,
		"question": "In which of the following tab an error is shown?",
		"answer": ["Profiler", "Logcat", "CPU", "Memory"],
		"category": "android",
		"correctAnswer": "Logcat"
	}, {
		"id": 26,
		"question": "Which of the following is the topmost layer of android architecture?",
		"answer": ["System Libraries and Android Runtime", "Applications Framework", "Applications", "Linux Kernel"],
		"category": "android",
		"correctAnswer": "Applications"
	}, {
		"id": 27,
		"question": "Which of the layer is the lowest layer of android architecture?",
		"answer": ["Applications", "Applications Framework", "Linux Kernel", "System Libraries and Android Runtime"],
		"category": "android",
		"correctAnswer": "Linux Kernel"
	}, {
		"id": 28,
		"question": "What is contained in manifest.xml?",
		"answer": ["List of strings used in the app", "Source code", "App assests", "Permission that the application requires"],
		"category": "android",
		"correctAnswer": "Permission that the application requires"
	}, {
		"id": 29,
		"question": "Which of the following is not a state in the service lifecycle?",
		"answer": ["Paused", "Destroyed", "Running", "Start"],
		"category": "android",
		"correctAnswer": "Paused"
	}, {
		"id": 30,
		"question": "Which of the following is not a nickname of any android version?",
		"answer": ["Honeycomb", "Muffin", "Donut", "Cupcake"],
		"category": "android",
		"correctAnswer": "Muffin"
	}, {
		"id": 31,
		"question": "Which of the following is a dialog class in android?",
		"answer": ["AlertDialog", "DatePicker Dialog", "AlertDialog", "All of the above"],
		"category": "android",
		"correctAnswer": "All of the above"
	}, {
		"id": 32,
		"question": "Which of the following is a dialog class in android?",
		"category": "android",
		"answer": ["ProgressDialog", "AlertDialog", "DatePicker Dialog", "All of the above"],
		"correctAnswer": "All of the above"
	}, {
		"id": 33,
		"question": "In which state the activity is, if it is not in focus, but still visible on the screen?",
		"category": "android",
		"answer": ["Paused state", "Destroyed state", "Rest State", "Running state"],
		"correctAnswer": "Paused state"
	}, {
		"id": 34,
		"question": "Which of the following is the built-in database of Android?",
		"category": "android",
		"answer": ["Oracle", "MySQL", "SQLite", "MongoDB"],
		"correctAnswer": "SQLite"
	}, {
		"id": 35,
		"question": "Android is developed by ",
		"category": "android",
		"answer": ["Samsung", "Microsoft", "Google", "Android Inc"],
		"correctAnswer": "Android Inc"
	}, {
		"id": 36,
		"question": "Android Web Browser Is Based On",
		"category": "android",
		"answer": ["Open-source Webkit", "Chrome", "Firefox", "Safari"],
		"correctAnswer": "Open-source Webkit"
	}, {
		"id": 37,
		"question": "Which Media Format Is Not Supported By Android",
		"category": "android",
		"answer": ["AVI", "MPEG", "MP4", "MIDI"],
		"correctAnswer": "AVI"
	}, {
		"id": 38,
		"question": "In Which Directory  XML Layout Files Are Stored",
		"category": "android",
		"answer": ["/res/values", "/res/layout", "/assets", "/src"],
		"correctAnswer": "/res/layout"
	}, {
		"id": 39,
		"question": "View Pager Is Used For",
		"category": "android",
		"answer": ["Paging Down List Items", "Swiping Activities", "Paging Down List Items", "Swiping Fragments"],
		"correctAnswer": "Swiping Fragments"
	}, {
		"id": 40,
		"question": "What Is JNI In Android?",
		"category": "android",
		"answer": ["Image Editable Tool", "Java Network Interface", "Java Native Interface", "Java Interface"],
		"correctAnswer": "Java Native Interface"
	}, {
		"id": 41,
		"question": "ANR in android stands for -",
		"category": "android",
		"answer": ["Application Not Responding", "Application Not Rendering", "Application Not Reacting", "None of the above"],
		"correctAnswer": "Application Not Responding"
	}, {
		"id": 42,
		"question": "All layout classes are the subclasses of -",
		"category": "android",
		"answer": ["android.view.ViewGroup", "android.view.View", "android.widget", "None of the above"],
		"correctAnswer": "android.view.ViewGroup"
	}, {
		"id": 43,
		"question": "Which of the following class in android executes the task asynchronously with your service?",
		"category": "android",
		"answer": ["AsyncTask", "SyncTask", "Both of the above", "Main Thread"],
		"correctAnswer": "AsyncTask"
	}, {
		"id": 44,
		"question": "Which of the following layout in android arranges its children into rows and columns?",
		"category": "android",
		"answer": ["RowLayout", "FrameLayout", "TableLayout", "LinearLayout"],
		"correctAnswer": "TableLayout"
	}, {
		"id": 45,
		"question": "Which of the following layout in android aligns all children either vertically or horizontally?",
		"category": "android",
		"answer": ["LinearLayout", "RelativeLayout", "TableLayout", "FrameLayout"],
		"correctAnswer": "LinearLayout"
	}, {
		"id": 46,
		"question": "What is the default value of the orientation attribute in LinearLayout?",
		"category": "android",
		"answer": ["Vertical", "Horizontal", "There is no default value of orientation attribute in LinearLayout", "None of the above"],
		"correctAnswer": "Horizontal"
	}, {
		"id": 47,
		"question": "What is the nine-patch images tool in android?",
		"category": "android",
		"answer": ["It is an image extension tool.", "It is used to change the bitmap images into nine sections", "Both (a) and (b)", "Both (a) and (b)"],
		"correctAnswer": "It is used to change the bitmap images into nine sections"
	}, {
		"id": 48,
		"question": "GCM in android stands for -",
		"category": "android",
		"answer": ["Google Count Messaging", "Google Center Messaging", "Google Cloud Messaging", "None of the above"],
		"correctAnswer": "Google Cloud Messaging"
	}, {
		"id": 49,
		"question": "Number of primitive data types in Java are?",
		"category": "java",
		"answer": ["6", "4", "5", "8"],
		"correctAnswer": "8"
	}, {
		"id": 50,
		"question": "Automatic type conversion is possible in which of the possible cases?",
		"category": "java",
		"answer": ["Long to int", "Byte to int", "Int to long", "Short to int"],
		"correctAnswer": "Int to long"
	}, {
		"id": 51,
		"question": "Select the valid statement.",
		"category": "java",
		"answer": ["char[] ch = new char[5]", "char[] ch = new char()", "char[] ch = new char(5)", "char[] ch = new char[]"],
		"correctAnswer": "char[] ch = new char[5]"
	}, {
		"id": 52,
		"question": "When an array is passed to a method, what does the method receive?",
		"category": "java",
		"answer": ["Copy of first element", "A copy of the array", "Length of the array", "The reference of the array"],
		"correctAnswer": "The reference of the array"
	}, {
		"id": 53,
		"question": "Select the valid statement to declare and initialize an array.",
		"category": "java",
		"answer": ["int[] A = (1, 3, 5)", "int[] A = {}", "int[] A = {1, 3, 5}", "int[][] A = {1, 3, 5}"],
		"correctAnswer": "int[] A = {1, 3, 5}"
	}, {
		"id": 54,
		"question": "When is the object created with new keyword?",
		"category": "java",
		"answer": ["At run time", "None", "Depends on the code", "At compile time"],
		"correctAnswer": "At run time"
	}, {
		"id": 55,
		"question": "In which of the following is toString() method defined?",
		"category": "java",
		"answer": ["java.lang.util", "java.lang.Object", "java.lang.String", "None"],
		"correctAnswer": "java.lang.Object"
	}, {
		"id": 56,
		"question": "what compareTo() returns?",
		"category": "java",
		"answer": ["An int value", "true", "false", "None"],
		"correctAnswer": "An int value"
	}, {
		"id": 57,
		"question": "\nIdentify the return type of a method that does not return any value.",
		"category": "java",
		"answer": ["int", "main", "null", "void"],
		"correctAnswer": "void"
	}, {
		"id": 58,
		"question": "Where does the system stores parameters and local variables whenever a method is invoked?",
		"category": "java",
		"answer": ["Stack", "Heap", "Tree", "Hash"],
		"correctAnswer": "Stack"
	}, {
		"id": 59,
		"question": "Which animal is known as the (Ship of the Desert)?",
		"category": "gk",
		"answer": ["Camel", "Dog", "Horse", "Lion"],
		"correctAnswer": "Camel"
	}, {
		"id": 60,
		"question": "How many hours are there in 1 day?",
		"category": "gk",
		"answer": ["20 hours", "24 hours", "23 hours", "22 hours"],
		"correctAnswer": "24 hours"
	}, {
		"id": 61,
		"question": "How many days are there in 1 week?",
		"category": "gk",
		"answer": ["5 days", "8 days", "7 days", "6 days"],
		"correctAnswer": "7 days"
	}, {
		"id": 62,
		"question": "How many letters are there in the English alphabet?",
		"category": "gk",
		"answer": ["20 letters", "25 letters", "24 letters", "26 letters"],
		"correctAnswer": "26 letters"
	}, {
		"id": 63,
		"question": "How many colours a rainbow have?",
		"category": "gk",
		"answer": ["7 colours", "3 colours", "5 colours", "6 colours"],
		"correctAnswer": "7 colours"
	}, {
		"id": 64,
		"question": "How many days are there in one year?",
		"category": "gk",
		"answer": ["350 days", "365 days", "360 days", "355 days"],
		"correctAnswer": "365 days"
	}, {
		"id": 65,
		"question": "How many minutes are there in one hour?",
		"category": "gk",
		"answer": ["60 minutes", "30 minutes", "40 minutes", "70 minutes"],
		"correctAnswer": "60 minutes"
	}, {
		"id": 66,
		"question": "How many centimetre are there in one meter? ",
		"category": "gk",
		"answer": ["10 cm", "100 cm", "1000 cm", "1 cm"],
		"correctAnswer": "100 cm"
	}, {
		"id": 67,
		"question": "How may meters in one kilometer?",
		"category": "gk",
		"answer": ["100 m", "500 m", "1000 m", "10 m"],
		"correctAnswer": "1000 m"
	}, {
		"id": 68,
		"question": "How many consonants are there in the English alphabet?",
		"category": "gk",
		"answer": ["20", "22", "24", "21"],
		"correctAnswer": "21"
	}, {
		"id": 69,
		"question": "How many vowels are there in the English alphabet?",
		"category": "gk",
		"answer": ["5 vowels ", "7 vowels ", "8 vowels ", "4 vowels "],
		"correctAnswer": "5 vowels "
	}, {
		"id": 70,
		"question": "Which animal is not a pet commonly?",
		"category": "gk",
		"answer": ["A Dog", "A Cat", "A Goat", "A Lion"],
		"correctAnswer": "A Lion"
	}, {
		"id": 71,
		"question": "Find the uncommon one?",
		"category": "gk",
		"answer": ["Dog", "Cat", "Goat", "Shark"],
		"correctAnswer": "Shark"
	}, {
		"id": 72,
		"question": "Find the uncommon one?",
		"category": "gk",
		"answer": ["Cricket", "Golf", "Footbal", "Kabaddi"],
		"correctAnswer": "Kabaddi"
	}, {
		"id": 73,
		"question": "Find the uncommon one?",
		"category": "gk",
		"answer": ["Car", "Mobile", "Cycle", "Bus"],
		"correctAnswer": "Mobile"
	}, {
		"id": 74,
		"question": "Animal normally known as.. King of the Jungle",
		"category": "gk",
		"answer": ["Tiger", "Fox", "Lion", "Elephant"],
		"correctAnswer": "Lion"
	}, {
		"id": 75,
		"question": "Capital of India?",
		"category": "gk",
		"answer": ["Mumbai", "New Delhi", "Gandhinagar", "Bihar"],
		"correctAnswer": "New Delhi"
	}, {
		"id": 76,
		"question": "Find the uncommon one?",
		"category": "gk",
		"answer": ["India", "China", "US", "Bhopal"],
		"correctAnswer": "Bhopal"
	}, {
		"id": 77,
		"question": "Find the uncommon one?",
		"category": "gk",
		"answer": ["Orange", "Green", "Blue", "Fish"],
		"correctAnswer": "Fish"
	}, {
		"id": 78,
		"question": "National animal of India",
		"category": "gk",
		"answer": ["Tiger", "Elephant", "Horse", "Lion"],
		"correctAnswer": "Tiger"
	}, {
		"id": 79,
		"question": "National birt of India?",
		"category": "gk",
		"answer": ["Peacock", "Pigeon", "Sparrow", "Eagle"],
		"correctAnswer": "Peacock"
	}, {
		"id": 80,
		"question": "National flower of India?",
		"category": "gk",
		"answer": ["Rose", "Lotus", "Lily", "Sunflower"],
		"correctAnswer": "Lotus"
	}, {
		"id": 81,
		"question": "National fruit of India?",
		"category": "gk",
		"answer": ["Orange", "Apple", "Banana", "Mango"],
		"correctAnswer": "Mango"
	}, {
		"id": 82,
		"question": "Name the primary colours?",
		"category": "gk",
		"answer": ["Red, Yellow and Blue", "Green, Orange and Red", "Blue, White and Gray", "Green, Red and White"],
		"correctAnswer": "Red, Yellow and Blue"
	}, {
		"id": 83,
		"question": "Smallest month of the year?",
		"category": "gk",
		"answer": ["March", "February", "October", "April"],
		"correctAnswer": "February"
	}, {
		"id": 84,
		"question": "Who was the first Prime Minister of India?",
		"category": "gk",
		"answer": ["Indira Gandhi", "Mahatma Gandhi", "Sardar Vallabhbhai Patel ", "Pandit Jawaharlal Nehru"],
		"correctAnswer": "Pandit Jawaharlal Nehru"
	}, {
		"id": 85,
		"question": "Which festival is called the festival of colours?",
		"category": "gk",
		"answer": ["Diwali", "Holi", "Lohri", "Rakhi"],
		"correctAnswer": "Holi"
	}, {
		"id": 86,
		"question": "The national aquatic animal of India?",
		"category": "gk",
		"answer": ["River Dolphin", "White cheeked shark", "Starfish", "Goldfish"],
		"correctAnswer": "River Dolphin"
	}, {
		"id": 87,
		"question": "The planet known as the Red Planet?",
		"category": "gk",
		"answer": ["Mercury", "Earth", "Jupiter", "Mars"],
		"correctAnswer": "Mars"
	}, {
		"id": 88,
		"question": "The country known as the Land of the Rising Sun?",
		"category": "gk",
		"answer": ["Japan", "India", "USA", "Hong Kong"],
		"correctAnswer": "Japan"
	}, {
		"id": 89,
		"question": "How many millimeters are there in a centimeters?",
		"category": "gk",
		"answer": ["15mm", "20mm", "1mm", "10mm"],
		"correctAnswer": "10mm"
	}, {
		"id": 90,
		"question": "Name the hardest substance available on Earth?",
		"category": "gk",
		"answer": ["Diamond", "Gold", "Iron", "Silver"],
		"correctAnswer": "Diamond"
	}, {
		"id": 91,
		"question": "Name the shape that has ten sides?",
		"category": "gk",
		"answer": ["Octagon", "Decagon", "Polygon", "Hexagon"],
		"correctAnswer": "Decagon"
	}, {
		"id": 92,
		"question": "मुहावरा: दीवारों के ______ होना",
		"category": "hindi",
		"answer": ["नाक", "पैर", "हाथ", "कान"],
		"correctAnswer": "कान"
	}, {
		"id": 93,
		"question": "मुहावरा: आँख का _____",
		"category": "hindi",
		"answer": ["दर्द", "तारा", "चश्मा", "पानी"],
		"correctAnswer": "तारा"
	}, {
		"id": 94,
		"question": "मुहावरा: ____ को बाप बनाना",
		"category": "hindi",
		"answer": ["भाई", "गधे", "दोस्त", "शेर"],
		"correctAnswer": "गधे"
	}, {
		"id": 95,
		"question": "मुहावरा:  _____ पलटना",
		"category": "hindi",
		"answer": ["पासा", "बात", "कार", "बस"],
		"correctAnswer": "पासा"
	}, {
		"id": 96,
		"question": "मुहावरा: _____ कर चूर होना",
		"category": "hindi",
		"answer": ["खा", "नाच", "थक", "सो"],
		"correctAnswer": "थक"
	}, {
		"id": 97,
		"question": "मुहावरा: तिनके का _____",
		"category": "hindi",
		"answer": ["घर", "खाना", "दर्द", "सहारा"],
		"correctAnswer": "सहारा"
	}, {
		"id": 98,
		"question": "ऐसा शब्द बताइए कि जिससे फूल, मिठाई और फल बन जाए ?",
		"category": "hindi",
		"answer": ["रसमलाई", "गुलाब जामुन", "आम", "रबड़ी"],
		"correctAnswer": "गुलाब जामुन"
	}, {
		"id": 99,
		"question": "अगर आप अँधेरे कमरे में एक मोमबत्ती, एक लालटेन और एक दीया के साथ हैं तो सबसे पहले आप क्या जलाएँगे ?",
		"category": "hindi",
		"answer": ["मोमबत्ती", "लालटेन", "बल्ब", "माचिस"],
		"correctAnswer": "माचिस"
	}, {
		"id": 100,
		"question": "वह कौन – सा फूल है, जिसके पास कोई रंग और महक नहीं है ?",
		"category": "hindi",
		"answer": ["अप्रैल फूल", "गेंदा", "गुलाब", "आम"],
		"correctAnswer": "अप्रैल फूल"
	}, {
		"id": 101,
		"question": "ऐसी कौन – सी चीज है, जिसको जितना खींचा जाता है, वो उतनी हीं छोटी होती जाती है |",
		"category": "hindi",
		"answer": ["रबर", "रस्सी", "बात", "सिगरेट"],
		"correctAnswer": "सिगरेट"
	}, {
		"id": 102,
		"question": "ऐसा रूम, जिसकी खिड़की ना दरवाजा तो बताओ क्या ?",
		"category": "hindi",
		"answer": ["बाथरूम", "मशरूम", "बैडरूम", "डाइनिंग रूम"],
		"correctAnswer": "मशरूम"
	}, {
		"id": 103,
		"question": "गन्दा हूँ तो सफ़ेद, सांफ हूँ तो काला, कौन हूं मैं ?",
		"category": "hindi",
		"answer": ["बल्ब", "रबर", "वाइटबोर्ड", "ब्लैकबोर्ड"],
		"correctAnswer": "ब्लैकबोर्ड"
	}, {
		"id": 104,
		"question": "तीन रंगो की तीन आँख, जल्दी से बताओ मेरा नाम ?",
		"category": "hindi",
		"answer": ["ट्रैफिक लाइट", "नारियल", "जहाज", "उल्लू"],
		"correctAnswer": "ट्रैफिक लाइट"
	}, {
		"id": 105,
		"question": "कमरे को भर देता फिर भी जगह नहीं लेता, क्या है इसका नाम ?",
		"category": "hindi",
		"answer": ["रूई", "सोच", "हवा", "पानी"],
		"correctAnswer": "हवा"
	}, {
		"id": 106,
		"question": "नहीं रखोगे तो टूट जाऊंगा, बताओ क्या हूँ मैं ?",
		"category": "hindi",
		"answer": ["वादा", "कांच का बर्तन", "धयान", "बल्ब"],
		"correctAnswer": "वादा"
	}, {
		"id": 107,
		"question": "छोटा सा दाना, पट पट कर के फट जाता, लोगो के खाने काम मैं आता, बताओ मेरा नाम ?",
		"category": "hindi",
		"answer": ["आम", "पॉपकॉर्न", "मोती", "कंकर"],
		"correctAnswer": "पॉपकॉर्न"
	}, {
		"id": 108,
		"question": "खाना दोगे तो जिन्दा रहूँगा पानी दोगे तो मर जाऊंगा, बताओ मेरा नाम ?",
		"category": "hindi",
		"answer": ["कछुआ", "नाव", "उल्लू", "आग"],
		"correctAnswer": "आग"
	}, {
		"id": 109,
		"question": "एक थी खाली पॉकेट जिसमे कुछ था, जल्दी से बातो क्या ?",
		"category": "hindi",
		"answer": ["छेद", "पैसे", "टॉफी", "सीके"],
		"correctAnswer": "छेद"
	}, {
		"id": 110,
		"question": "तुम्हारे बोलने पे ही बजता हूँ, पर फिर ना जाने मेरे बजने से क्यों परेशान होते हो तुम ?",
		"category": "hindi",
		"answer": ["बैंड", "अलार्म", "कांच का बर्तन", "सीके"],
		"correctAnswer": "अलार्म"
	}, {
		"id": 111,
		"question": "जितना खाली करोगे उतना बढ़ा हो जाऊंगा, अगर समझ गए तो बताओ मेरा नाम ?",
		"category": "hindi",
		"answer": ["नारियल", "घर", "रेत का ढेर", "गड्ढा"],
		"correctAnswer": "गड्ढा"
	}, {
		"id": 112,
		"question": "वो क्या है जो बहती है पर ना नदी  है ना पानी है ?",
		"category": "hindi",
		"answer": ["नदी", "कूआ", "नाक", "हवा"],
		"correctAnswer": "नाक"
	}, {
		"id": 113,
		"question": "अकेला छोड़ो तो कुछ नहीं करूँगा, पर काटने जाओगे तो रुला दूंगा, अगर समझ गए तो बताओ मेरा नाम ?",
		"category": "hindi",
		"answer": ["आम", "प्याज", "नारियल", "मिर्ची"],
		"correctAnswer": "प्याज"
	}, {
		"id": 114,
		"question": "एक ऐसी सूई जो सबको रास्ता दिखाए, अगर समझ गए तो मेरा नाम बताएं ?",
		"category": "hindi",
		"answer": ["घडी", "सुई धागा", "कंपास", "ट्रैफिक लाइट"],
		"correctAnswer": "कंपास"
	}, {
		"id": 115,
		"question": "What are two things you can never eat for breakfast?",
		"category": "english",
		"answer": ["Mango and Orange", "Lunch and Dinner", "Pizza and Dinner", "Pasta and Noodel"],
		"correctAnswer": "Lunch and Dinner"
	}, {
		"id": 116,
		"question": "What is always coming but never arrives? ",
		"category": "english",
		"answer": ["Bus", "Time", "Tomorrow", "Today"],
		"correctAnswer": "Tomorrow"
	}, {
		"id": 117,
		"question": "What gets wetter the more it dries? ",
		"category": "english",
		"answer": ["Water", "Fire", "Bed", "Towel"],
		"correctAnswer": "Towel"
	}, {
		"id": 118,
		"question": "What word is spelled incorrectly in every single dictionary?",
		"category": "english",
		"answer": ["Dictionary", "Incorrectly", "Wrong", "Correct"],
		"correctAnswer": "Incorrectly"
	}, {
		"id": 119,
		"question": "What never asks a question but gets answered all the time?",
		"category": " english",
		"answer": ["Student", "Dog", "Cellphone", "Teacher"],
		"correctAnswer": "Cellphone"
	}, {
		"id": 120,
		"question": "What word would you use to describe a man who does not have all his fingers on one hand?",
		"category": " english",
		"answer": ["Handicap", "Normal", "Supernatural", "Ghost"],
		"correctAnswer": "Normal"
	}, {
		"id": 121,
		"question": "What goes up but never ever comes down?",
		"category": " english",
		"answer": ["Petrol Price", "Bullet", "Your age", "Your weight"],
		"correctAnswer": "Your age"
	}, {
		"id": 122,
		"question": "He got too tired _____ over work.",
		"category": " english",
		"answer": ["in", "because off", "on", "because of"],
		"correctAnswer": "because of"
	}, {
		"id": 123,
		"question": "He was seen _____ to the school.",
		"category": " english",
		"answer": ["going", "went", "goes", "go"],
		"correctAnswer": "going"
	}, {
		"id": 124,
		"question": "Opposite of men?",
		"category": " english",
		"answer": ["Man", "Women", "Boy", "Girl"],
		"correctAnswer": "Women"
	}, {
		"id": 125,
		"question": "I _____ never seen such a picture before.",
		"category": " english",
		"answer": ["did", "was", "were", "have"],
		"correctAnswer": "have"
	}, {
		"id": 126,
		"question": "What has a face and two hands, but no arms or legs?",
		"category": " english",
		"answer": ["Car", "Bat", "Clock", "Remote"],
		"correctAnswer": "Clock"
	}, {
		"id": 127,
		"question": "I start out tall, but the longer I stand, the shorter I grow. What am I?",
		"category": " english",
		"answer": ["A candle", "A boy", "A bulb", "A chair"],
		"correctAnswer": "A candle"
	}, {
		"id": 128,
		"question": "Some months have 31 days, others have 30 days, but how many have 28 days?",
		"category": " english",
		"answer": ["5", "1", "12", "6"],
		"correctAnswer": "12"
	}, {
		"id": 129,
		"question": "Meaning of \"Chicken Feed\".",
		"category": " english",
		"answer": ["A very small money", "Very expensive", "Food for thought", "None of these"],
		"correctAnswer": "A very small money"
	}, {
		"id": 130,
		"question": "What has a head, a tail, but does not have a body?",
		"category": "english",
		"answer": [" A snack", "A coin", "A bus", "A bat"],
		"correctAnswer": "A coin"
	}, {
		"id": 131,
		"question": "अगर नाक पर मैं चढ़ जाऊँ,\nतो कान पकड़कर खूब पढ़ाऊँ |",
		"category": "hindi",
		"answer": ["चश्मा", "तितली", "गुस्सा", "हवा"],
		"correctAnswer": "चश्मा"
	}, {
		"id": 132,
		"question": "मेरे नाम से सब डरते हैं, मेरे लिए परिश्रम करते हैं |",
		"category": "hindi",
		"answer": ["पानी", "परीक्षा", "मिर्ची", "आग"],
		"correctAnswer": "परीक्षा"
	}, {
		"id": 133,
		"question": "मैं मरती हूँ, मैं कटती हूँ |\nपर रोते हो तुम, पहचानो कौन हूँ मैं |",
		"category": "hindi",
		"answer": ["प्याज", "रूई", "मिर्ची", "मोमबत्ती"],
		"correctAnswer": "प्याज"
	}, {
		"id": 134,
		"question": "What goes up as soon as the rain comes down?",
		"category": "english",
		"answer": ["Fire", "An umbrella", "Electricity", "Water"],
		"correctAnswer": "An umbrella"
	}, {
		"id": 135,
		"question": "I have all the knowledge you have. But I’m so small, you can hold me in your fist. What am I?",
		"category": "english",
		"answer": ["Your teacher", "Your mobile", "Your parents", "Your brain"],
		"correctAnswer": "Your brain"
	}, {
		"id": 136,
		"question": "What has a neck but no head?",
		"category": "english",
		"answer": ["A fish", "A bottle", "A boy", "A glass"],
		"correctAnswer": "A bottle"
	}, {
		"id": 137,
		"question": "If you were running a race and passed the person in second place, what place would you be in now?",
		"category": "english",
		"answer": ["First", "Third", "Second", "Last"],
		"correctAnswer": "Second"
	}, {
		"id": 138,
		"question": "If you threw a red rock into a blue sea, what would it come back as? ",
		"category": "english",
		"answer": ["Blue rock", "Wet rock", "No rock", "Purple rock"],
		"correctAnswer": "Wet rock"
	}, {
		"id": 139,
		"question": "Which plant gives us medicines?",
		"category": "science",
		"answer": ["Tulsi", "Castor oil", "Dhatura", "All of these"],
		"correctAnswer": "All of these"
	}, {
		"id": 140,
		"question": "Oil yielding plants are:",
		"category": "science",
		"answer": ["Rice", "Mustard", "Wheat", "Rice"],
		"correctAnswer": "Mustard"
	}, {
		"id": 141,
		"question": "Honey comes from beehives of:",
		"category": "science",
		"answer": ["Butterfly", "Spider", "Honeybee", "None of these"],
		"correctAnswer": "Honeybee"
	}, {
		"id": 142,
		"question": "_____ is extracted by a honey extractor from beehives.",
		"category": "science",
		"answer": ["Honey", "Sugar", "Sarbat", "All of these"],
		"correctAnswer": "Honey"
	}, {
		"id": 143,
		"question": "A small white structure may have grown out of seeds is called:",
		"category": "science",
		"answer": ["Roots", "Stem", "Sprouts", "None of these"],
		"correctAnswer": "sprouts"
	}, {
		"id": 144,
		"question": "Bees collect nectar from:",
		"category": "science",
		"answer": ["Flowers", "Fruits", "Flowers", "None of these"],
		"correctAnswer": "flowers"
	}, {
		"id": 145,
		"question": "Bees store nectar for their use all through the:",
		"category": "science",
		"answer": ["Week", "Year", "Month", "Day"],
		"correctAnswer": "Year"
	}, {
		"id": 146,
		"question": "Eggs are the rich source of:",
		"category": "science",
		"answer": ["Carbohydrates", "Proteins", "Fat", "Oil"],
		"correctAnswer": "Proteins"
	}, {
		"id": 147,
		"question": "Fruits are:",
		"category": "science",
		"answer": ["Tasty", "All of these", "Delicious", "Juicy"],
		"correctAnswer": "all of these"
	}, {
		"id": 148,
		"question": "Honey bee prepare honey in beehives.",
		"category": "science",
		"answer": ["True", "False"],
		"correctAnswer": "True"
	}, {
		"id": 149,
		"question": "Animals eat both plants and animals.",
		"category": "science",
		"answer": ["False", "True"],
		"correctAnswer": "True"
	}, {
		"id": 150,
		"question": "Fish are major sources of proteins.",
		"category": "science",
		"answer": ["True", "False"],
		"correctAnswer": "True"
	}, {
		"id": 151,
		"question": "Food helps in body buildings.",
		"category": "science",
		"answer": ["True", "False"],
		"correctAnswer": "True"
	}, {
		"id": 152,
		"question": "Those animals that eating other animals are called:",
		"category": "science",
		"answer": ["Carnivores", "Omnivores", "Herbivores", "None of these"],
		"correctAnswer": "Carnivores"
	}, {
		"id": 153,
		"question": "_____ is the ability to do work.",
		"category": "science",
		"answer": ["Strength", "Hard work", "Energy", "None of these"],
		"correctAnswer": "Energy"
	}, {
		"id": 154,
		"question": "Animals which not give us milk",
		"category": "science",
		"answer": ["Tiger", "Cows", "Camel", "Goat"],
		"correctAnswer": "Tiger"
	}, {
		"id": 155,
		"question": "Which part of the Brinjal plant we generally eat ?",
		"category": "science",
		"answer": ["Fruit", "Branches", "Root", "Seeds"],
		"correctAnswer": "fruit"
	}, {
		"id": 156,
		"question": "Which part of sugarcane we generally eat?",
		"category": "science",
		"answer": ["Root", "Stem/Branch", "Leaves", "Seeds"],
		"correctAnswer": "Stem/Branch"
	}, {
		"id": 157,
		"question": "Plants gives us more varieties of:",
		"category": "science",
		"answer": ["Milk", "Gas", "Food", "Curd"],
		"correctAnswer": "Food"
	}, {
		"id": 158,
		"question": "Sugar is obtained from the leaves of sugarcane.",
		"category": "science",
		"answer": ["True", "False"],
		"correctAnswer": "False"
	}, {
		"id": 159,
		"question": "Tiger is a Omnivores.",
		"category": "science",
		"answer": ["False", "True"],
		"correctAnswer": "False"
	}, {
		"id": 160,
		"question": "An oily thin paper sheet will be:",
		"category": "science",
		"answer": ["Translucent", "Transparent", "Opaque", "Cannot be predicted"],
		"correctAnswer": "translucent"
	}, {
		"id": 161,
		"question": "Which is a set of transparent materials?",
		"category": "science",
		"answer": ["Glass and air", "Water and glass", "Water and air", "All of these"],
		"correctAnswer": "All of these"
	}, {
		"id": 162,
		"question": "Choose the opaque object from the following:",
		"category": "science",
		"answer": ["Water", "Charcoal", "Glass", "Air"],
		"correctAnswer": "Charcoal"
	}, {
		"id": 163,
		"question": "Which object shines?",
		"category": "science",
		"answer": ["Cotton shirt", "Steel spoon", "Plastic toy", "Stone piece"],
		"correctAnswer": "Steel spoon"
	}, {
		"id": 164,
		"question": "Which of the following has reddish brown colour?",
		"category": "science",
		"answer": ["Iron", "Gold", "Copper", "Silver"],
		"correctAnswer": "Iron"
	}, {
		"id": 165,
		"question": "Which one of the following is insoluble in water?",
		"category": "science",
		"answer": ["Milk", "Alcohol", "Sugar", "Oil"],
		"correctAnswer": "Oil"
	}, {
		"id": 166,
		"question": "The amount of matter in any object is called its weight.",
		"category": "science",
		"answer": ["False", "True"],
		"correctAnswer": "False"
	}]
}